Multithreading programming execute multiple instruction to modify speed of completing tasks multithreading uses CPU cores Multithreading refers to a program that can take advantage of a multicore computer

Parallel programming its mode of completing operations in which procces splits into parts and at the same time executes on different proccessors and send result to the computer parallel programming is impossible in computer with one proccessor

Asynchronous programming is a means of parallel programming in which a unit of work runs separately from the main application thread and notifies the calling thread of its completion, failure or progress.The main benefits one can gain from using asynchronous programming are improved application performance and responsiveness

Примеры для каждого типа
Вы взяли лопату и копаете. Это однопоточная работа
Вы пригласили друга Васю и копаете вместе, периодически задевая друг-друга лопатами. Это многопоточная работа
Пока вы копаете бассейн, Вася копает канаву под водопровод. Никто никому не мешает. Это паралельная работа
Вы пригласили бригаду землекопов, а сами с Васей пошли играть в CS:GO. Когда бригада все сделает, к вам придут за деньгами. Это асинхронная работа
количество лопат-количество ядер в процессоре